Wuqi **Zhang**

Also known as William Aaron Cheung Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science and Engineering

Room 3663, Academic Building, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Clear Water Bay, Hong Kong Room

I am currently a Ph.D. candidate supervised by professor Shing-Chi Cheung at The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST) with a research focus: software engineering, especially in software testing and analysis. As a member of the CASTLE Research Group at HKUST, it is very nice to work with a professional and very kind professor, as well as a group of innovative researchers.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering 2019 - Present

CGA: 3.933/4.3

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong.

2015 - 2019 B.Eng. in Computer Science and Technology

GPA: 4.2149/5 (Rank: 1/250), Outstanding Graduates

Northeastern University, China

Research Interests

RESEARCH FOCUS Software Engineering, Software Testing, Program Analysis APPLICATION TO Blockchain, Smart Contracts, Decentralized Applications OTHER INTERESTS Web Fingerprinting, Deep Learning System Testing

Publications

Front-Running Attack Benchmark Construction and Vulnerability Detection Technique Evaluation 2022

Wuqi Zhang, Lili Wei, Shing-Chi Cheung, Yepang Liu, Shuqing Li, Lu Liu, and Michael R. Lyu Preprint

arXiv:2212.12110

2022 Surakav: Generating Realistic Traces for a Strong Website Fingerprinting Defense

Jiajun Gong, Wuqi Zhang, Charles Zhang, Tao Wang Conference

In Proceedings of the 43rd IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (IEEE S&P 2022), May 23-26, 2022, San Francisco, United States.

Fast Test Input Generation for Finding Deviated Behaviors in Compressed Deep Neural Network 2021

Yongqiang Tian, Wuqi Zhang, Ming Wen, Shing-Chi Cheung, Chengnian Sun, Shiqing Ma, Yu Jiang Preprint arXiv:2112.02819

WFDefProxy: Modularly Implementing and Empirically Evaluating Website Fingerprinting Defenses

2021

Preprint Jiajun Gong, Wuqi Zhang, Charles Zhang, Tao Wang

arXiv:2111.12629

2021 ĐArcher: Detecting On-Chain-Off-Chain Synchronization Bugs In Decentralized Applications

Conference Wuqi Zhang, Lili Wei, Shuqing Li, Yepang Liu, Shing-Chi Cheung

In Proceedings of the 29th ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the

Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE '21), August 23-28, 2021, Athens, Greece.

Characterizing Transaction-Reverting Statements in Ethereum Smart Contracts 2021

Conference Lu Liu, Lili Wei, Wuqi Zhang, Ming Wen, Yepang Liu, Shing-Chi Cheung

In Proceedings of the 34th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE

'21), November 14-20, 2021, Melbourne, Australia.

Exploration on the Reform of Laboratory Integrated Management System in Colleges and Universities 2018

Wuqi Zhang, Xingyu Wang, Yi Sha, Lili Zhang Journal

Research and Exploration in Laboratory, 2018, 37(11): 149-152.



	The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
2022	Research Travel Grant
	The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
2022	HKUST RedBird Academic Excellence Award
	The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
2019	Postgraduate Studentship
	The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
2019	Outstanding Graduates of Liaoning Province
	Department of Education of Liaoning, China
2018	Second-class University Scholarship
	Northeastern University, China
2018	Excellent Student Award
	Northeastern University, China
2017	National Scholarship
	Ministry of Education of the People's Republic of China
2017	First-class University Scholarship
	Northeastern University, China
2017	Pacemaker to Excellent Student Award
	Northeastern University, China
2016	National Scholarship
	Ministry of Education of the People's Republic of China
2016	First-class University Scholarship
	Northeastern University, China
2016	Pacemaker to Excellent Student Award
	Northeastern University, China

TEACHING

2021-2022 Fall Teaching Assistant for COMP3021 Java Programming, HKUST 2020-2021 Spring Teaching Assistant for COMP5111 Fundamentals of Software Analysis, HKUST 2020-2021 Fall Teaching Assistant for COMP3021 Java Programming, HKUST

I VISITING EXPERIENCE

Research

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong, China

2019

- > Topic : Vulnerability Detection in Ethereum Smart Contracts
- > Adviser: Professor Shing-Chi Cheung
- > March, 2019 May, 2019

Research Internship

Research

North Carolina State University, NORTH CAROLINA, U.S.A.

2018

> Topic: Multiple Peaks Phenomenon in Non-Markovian Epidemics on Multilayer Networks

- > Adviser : Professor Huaiyu Dai
- > July, 2018 August, 2018

Summer Research Program



WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineering 2020-2021

Hong Kong Applied Science and Technology Research Institute (ASTRI), Hong Kong, China

This is a joint project between ASTRI and Crypto-FinTech Lab of HKUST to develop the next-generation distributed file system based on blockchain and distributed computing technologies.

> October 2020 - June 2021 Blockchain FinTech Smart Contracts

Engineering 2018-2019

Shenyang Wuzhi Technology Co., Ltd., LIAONING, China

The company was funded by alumni of Northeastern University. The work in this company was to develop the back-end server of the mobile application that automatically translates sign language to Chinese.

> October 2018 - January 2019
RESTful Service | Sever-side Development |

Engineering 2015-2019

Publicity Department of Northeastern University, LIAONING, China

The work is to continuously maintain various University websites as one of the technical leaders in the student association.

> October 2015 - June 2019 Web Development RESTful Service